Pedr Browne

Software Engineer

I'm a software engineer with almost two decades of experience, focussing on front-end app development within the React ecosystem, but drawing from experience building server-based sites and mobile apps. I write lean, well-tested code using the best bits of functional programming while keeping the code easy to read and reason-about. I'm comfortable collaborating on prototypes and with designers, defining and refining spec alongside engineers, or discussing features with stakeholders. Pragmatic in my approach, adaptable and inquisitive, I find the work I do endlessly interesting, and ultimately very satisfying. If I wasn't writing code for a living. I'd be doing it for fun.

+44 (0)7880 600 363
info@undistraction.com
undistraction.com
Newcastle Upon Tyne, UK
github.com/undistraction
linkedin.com/in/pedr-browne

Core Skills

- JavaScript 10 years+.
- React ecosystem 8 years.
- TypeScript 1 year.
- CSS 10 years+ (Tailwind, Styled-Components, CSS Modules, Sass).
- Backend experience with Rails, Node and Next.
- Experience across development process from specification, through design/UX, wire-framing, prototyping, build, revision, and QA.
- Strong emphasis on unit, e2e and component testing (Jest, Vitest, Cypress, Playwright).
- Git, including Github and Gitlab workflows
- VSCode with Copilot and Claude
- Maintained CI pipelines (Gitlab CI, GitHub Acts.).

- Experienced with consuming and specifying RESTful and GraphQL APIs, both cookie-based and JWT auth (URQL, React Query, Axios).
- Written and maintained complex docs and style guides (Storybook, Postman).
- Familiar with common development tooling, including Webpack, Vite, Babel, ESlint, Prettier, Husky, Committent, Semantic Release etc.
- Researching and evaluating technologies: third-party code, platforms and infrastructure
- Comfortable working remotely, independently or closely as part of a team.
- Quick to adapt to different working environments and project management styles.
- Drive to learn and experiment with new tech.

Employment History

Sleepstation

Lead Front-End Developer
Jul 2018–May 2024
Insomnia Treatment App
sleepstation.org.uk
React, Redux, Styled-components, GraphQL,
Jest, Cypress, Storybook, Gatsby, Rails

- Front-end lead role on product dev team.
- Architected, built, and maintained multiple FEs for service-users and company personel.
- Worked closely with designers, front- and back-end developers and Technical Director to define requirements, estimates and timelines.
- Maintained monorepo, documentation, unit and e2e tests, styleguide, Gitlab CI pipelines.
- Mentored junior developers through paired programming and collaborative code reviews.

From 2005–2018 I worked as a Software engineer, consultant, and web developer, engineering solutions for a wide variety of clients. The following is a small selection of my clients from that period.

Scribblar

Senior Front-End Developer & UX Designer 2017–18
Collaborative whiteboard scribblar.com
React, Styled-Components, Jest

TriNetX

Senior Front-End Developer 2015–2017 Pharmaceutical trial and research platform trinetx.com React, Redux, Sass, Styled-components, Jest

Intercity

Full-Stack Developer 2015–2018 intercitystudio.com Branding and design consultancy Rails, Sass, JavaScript

Institute of Development Studies (IDS)

Web Developer
2014–2016
ids.ac.uk
Educational and research institution
Rails, Sass, JavaScript

Recent Personal Projects

github.com/undistraction/coons-patch TypeScript, Vitest.

Package for creating a coons-patch surface from cubic Bezier curves and calculating the coordinates of surface points.

github.com/undistraction/warp-grid

TypeScript, Vitest.

Package providing a fully-featured grid system for a deformable two-dimensional grid including access to different types of interpolation and powerful configuration options for columns, rows, gutters and distribution.

- Worked with stakeholders to document and define functionality and approach to v2 of app.
- UI wireframes.
- App layout and component build.
- Worked on v1 of the app, from initial wireframes and prototypes to release to customers.
- Built complex components including charts and dashboards for exploring large data-sets.
- Worked closely with stakeholders, designers and UX to specify components and functionality.
- Built and maintained websites for Intercity's clients as well as their own company site.
- Worked closely with designers to deliver pixel-perfect layouts and diverse functionality.
- Built custom content-management systems.
- Designed and built research archive for Pathways, an NGO promoting Women's Rights.
- Designed and built educational platform and online interactive teaching resources for universities and community groups.

github.com/undistraction/warp-grid-editor TypeScript, React, Tailwind, Zustand, Vitest, Playwright.

App with complex GUI for editing warp grids, including project management features and export to code or SVG.